=== 0 ===
Title: Vision-Language Memory for Spatial Reasoning
ID: 2511.20644
Authors: Zuntao Liu, Yi Du, Taimeng Fu et al.
Date: 2025-11-25
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Spatial reasoning is a critical capability for intelligent robots, yet current vision-language models (VLMs) still fall short of human-level performance in video-based spatial reasoning. This gap main...

=== 1 ===
Title: Evaluating Gemini Robotics Policies in a Veo World Simulator
ID: 2512.10675
Authors: Gemini Robotics Team, Krzysztof Choromanski, Coline Devin et al.
Date: 2025-12-11
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV, cs.LG
Abstract: Generative world models hold significant potential for simulating interactions with visuomotor policies in varied environments. Frontier video models can enable generation of realistic observations an...

=== 2 ===
Title: OmniNWM: Omniscient Driving Navigation World Models
ID: 2510.18313
Authors: Bohan Li, Zhuang Ma, Dalong Du et al.
Date: 2025-10-21
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Autonomous driving world models are expected to work effectively across three core dimensions: state, action, and reward. Existing models, however, are typically restricted to limited state modalities...

=== 3 ===
Title: IGen: Scalable Data Generation for Robot Learning from Open-World Images
ID: 2512.01773
Authors: Chenghao Gu, Haolan Kang, Junchao Lin et al.
Date: 2025-12-01
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: The rise of generalist robotic policies has created an exponential demand for large-scale training data. However, on-robot data collection is labor-intensive and often limited to specific environments...

=== 4 ===
Title: RoboWheel: A Data Engine from Real-World Human Demonstrations for Cross-Embodiment Robotic Learning
ID: 2512.02729
Authors: Yuhong Zhang, Zihan Gao, Shengpeng Li et al.
Date: 2025-12-02
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: We introduce Robowheel, a data engine that converts human hand object interaction (HOI) videos into training-ready supervision for cross morphology robotic learning. From monocular RGB or RGB-D inputs...

=== 5 ===
Title: In-N-On: Scaling Egocentric Manipulation with in-the-wild and on-task Data
ID: 2511.15704
Authors: Xiongyi Cai, Ri-Zhao Qiu, Geng Chen et al.
Date: 2025-11-19
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV
Abstract: Egocentric videos are a valuable and scalable data source to learn manipulation policies. However, due to significant data heterogeneity, most existing approaches utilize human data for simple pre-tra...

=== 6 ===
Title: WholeBodyVLA: Towards Unified Latent VLA for Whole-Body Loco-Manipulation Control
ID: 2512.11047
Authors: Haoran Jiang, Jin Chen, Qingwen Bu et al.
Date: 2025-12-11
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV
Abstract: Humanoid robots require precise locomotion and dexterous manipulation to perform challenging loco-manipulation tasks. Yet existing approaches, modular or end-to-end, are deficient in manipulation-awar...

=== 7 ===
Title: MoE3D: Mixture of Experts meets Multi-Modal 3D Understanding
ID: 2511.22103
Authors: Yu Li, Yuenan Hou, Yingmei Wei et al.
Date: 2025-11-27
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Multi-modal 3D understanding is a fundamental task in computer vision. Previous multi-modal fusion methods typically employ a single, dense fusion network, struggling to handle the significant heterog...

=== 8 ===
Title: DynamicVerse: A Physically-Aware Multimodal Framework for 4D World Modeling
ID: 2512.03000
Authors: Kairun Wen, Yuzhi Huang, Runyu Chen et al.
Date: 2025-12-02
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Understanding the dynamic physical world, characterized by its evolving 3D structure, real-world motion, and semantic content with textual descriptions, is crucial for human-agent interaction and enab...

=== 9 ===
Title: 4DLangVGGT: 4D Language-Visual Geometry Grounded Transformer
ID: 2512.05060
Authors: Xianfeng Wu, Yajing Bai, Minghan Li et al.
Date: 2025-12-04
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Constructing 4D language fields is crucial for embodied AI, augmented/virtual reality, and 4D scene understanding, as they provide enriched semantic representations of dynamic environments and enable ...

=== 10 ===
Title: VGGDrive: Empowering Vision-Language Models with Cross-View Geometric Grounding for Autonomous Driving
ID: 2602.20794
Authors: Jie Wang, Guang Li, Zhijian Huang et al.
Date: 2026-02-24
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: The significance of cross-view 3D geometric modeling capabilities for autonomous driving is self-evident, yet existing Vision-Language Models (VLMs) inherently lack this capability, resulting in their...

=== 11 ===
Title: Continually Evolving Skill Knowledge in Vision Language Action Model
ID: 2511.18085
Authors: Yuxuan Wu, Guangming Wang, Zhiheng Yang et al.
Date: 2025-11-22
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: Developing general robot intelligence in open environments requires continual skill learning. Recent Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models leverage massive pretraining data to support diverse manipulati...

=== 12 ===
Title: HiMoE-VLA: Hierarchical Mixture-of-Experts for Generalist Vision-Language-Action Policies
ID: 2512.05693
Authors: Zhiying Du, Bei Liu, Yaobo Liang et al.
Date: 2025-12-05
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: The development of foundation models for embodied intelligence critically depends on access to large-scale, high-quality robot demonstration data. Recent approaches have sought to address this challen...

=== 13 ===
Title: ThinkMorph: Emergent Properties in Multimodal Interleaved Chain-of-Thought Reasoning
ID: 2510.27492
Authors: Jiawei Gu, Yunzhuo Hao, Huichen Will Wang et al.
Date: 2025-10-30
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Multimodal reasoning requires iterative coordination between language and vision, yet it remains unclear what constitutes a meaningful interleaved chain of thought. We posit that text and image though...

=== 14 ===
Title: Beyond Words and Pixels: A Benchmark for Implicit World Knowledge Reasoning in Generative Models
ID: 2511.18271
Authors: Tianyang Han, Junhao Su, Junjie Hu et al.
Date: 2025-11-23
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: Text-to-image (T2I) models today are capable of producing photorealistic, instruction-following images, yet they still frequently fail on prompts that require implicit world knowledge. Existing evalua...

=== 15 ===
Title: WorldModelBench: Judging Video Generation Models As World Models
ID: 2502.20694
Authors: Dacheng Li, Yunhao Fang, Yukang Chen et al.
Date: 2025-02-28
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: Video generation models have rapidly progressed, positioning themselves as video world models capable of supporting decision-making applications like robotics and autonomous driving. However, current ...

=== 16 ===
Title: PICABench: How Far Are We from Physically Realistic Image Editing?
ID: 2510.17681
Authors: Yuandong Pu, Le Zhuo, Songhao Han et al.
Date: 2025-10-20
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: Image editing has achieved remarkable progress recently. Modern editing models could already follow complex instructions to manipulate the original content. However, beyond completing the editing inst...

=== 17 ===
Title: PAI-Bench: A Comprehensive Benchmark For Physical AI
ID: 2512.01989
Authors: Fengzhe Zhou, Jiannan Huang, Jialuo Li et al.
Date: 2025-12-01
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Physical AI aims to develop models that can perceive and predict real-world dynamics; yet, the extent to which current multi-modal large language models and video generative models support these abili...

=== 18 ===
Title: ProPhy: Progressive Physical Alignment for Dynamic World Simulation
ID: 2512.05564
Authors: Zijun Wang, Panwen Hu, Jing Wang et al.
Date: 2025-12-05
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Recent advances in video generation have shown remarkable potential for constructing world simulators. However, current models still struggle to produce physically consistent results, particularly whe...

=== 19 ===
Title: WorldLens: Full-Spectrum Evaluations of Driving World Models in Real World
ID: 2512.10958
Authors: Ao Liang, Lingdong Kong, Tianyi Yan et al.
Date: 2025-12-11
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Generative world models are reshaping embodied AI, enabling agents to synthesize realistic 4D driving environments that look convincing but often fail physically or behaviorally. Despite rapid progres...

=== 20 ===
Title: Latent Chain-of-Thought World Modeling for End-to-End Driving
ID: 2512.10226
Authors: Shuhan Tan, Kashyap Chitta, Yuxiao Chen et al.
Date: 2025-12-11
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: Recent Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models for autonomous driving explore inference-time reasoning as a way to improve driving performance and safety in challenging scenarios. Most prior work uses nat...

=== 21 ===
Title: FutureX: Enhance End-to-End Autonomous Driving via Latent Chain-of-Thought World Model
ID: 2512.11226
Authors: Hongbin Lin, Yiming Yang, Yifan Zhang et al.
Date: 2025-12-12
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: In autonomous driving, end-to-end planners learn scene representations from raw sensor data and utilize them to generate a motion plan or control actions. However, exclusive reliance on the current sc...

=== 22 ===
Title: DriveWorld-VLA: Unified Latent-Space World Modeling with Vision-Language-Action for Autonomous Driving
ID: 2602.06521
Authors: Feiyang jia, Lin Liu, Ziying Song et al.
Date: 2026-02-06
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: End-to-end (E2E) autonomous driving has recently attracted increasing interest in unifying Vision-Language-Action (VLA) with World Models to enhance decision-making and forward-looking imagination. Ho...

=== 23 ===
Title: DriveFine: Refining-Augmented Masked Diffusion VLA for Precise and Robust Driving
ID: 2602.14577
Authors: Chenxu Dang, Sining Ang, Yongkang Li et al.
Date: 2026-02-16
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models for autonomous driving increasingly adopt generative planners trained with imitation learning followed by reinforcement learning. Diffusion-based planners suffer fr...

=== 24 ===
Title: MEM: Multi-Scale Embodied Memory for Vision Language Action Models
ID: 2603.03596
Authors: Marcel Torne, Karl Pertsch, Homer Walke et al.
Date: 2026-03-04
Categories: cs.RO, cs.LG
Abstract: Conventionally, memory in end-to-end robotic learning involves inputting a sequence of past observations into the learned policy. However, in complex multi-stage real-world tasks, the robot's memory m...

=== 25 ===
Title: OAT: Ordered Action Tokenization
ID: 2602.04215
Authors: Chaoqi Liu, Xiaoshen Han, Jiawei Gao et al.
Date: 2026-02-04
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.LG
Abstract: Autoregressive policies offer a compelling foundation for scalable robot learning by enabling discrete abstraction, token-level reasoning, and flexible inference. However, applying autoregressive mode...

=== 26 ===
Title: ActionCodec: What Makes for Good Action Tokenizers
ID: 2602.15397
Authors: Zibin Dong, Yicheng Liu, Shiduo Zhang et al.
Date: 2026-02-17
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models leveraging the native autoregressive paradigm of Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have demonstrated superior instruction-following and training efficiency. Central to ...

=== 27 ===
Title: Behavior Generation with Latent Actions
ID: 2403.03181
Authors: Seungjae Lee, Yibin Wang, Haritheja Etukuru et al.
Date: 2024-03-05
Categories: cs.LG, cs.AI, cs.RO
Abstract: Generative modeling of complex behaviors from labeled datasets has been a longstanding problem in decision making. Unlike language or image generation, decision making requires modeling actions - cont...

=== 28 ===
Title: RDT2: Exploring the Scaling Limit of UMI Data Towards Zero-Shot Cross-Embodiment Generalization
ID: 2602.03310
Authors: Songming Liu, Bangguo Li, Kai Ma et al.
Date: 2026-02-03
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV, cs.LG
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models hold promise for generalist robotics but currently struggle with data scarcity, architectural inefficiencies, and the inability to generalize across different hardw...

=== 29 ===
Title: Neural Implicit Action Fields: From Discrete Waypoints to Continuous Functions for Vision-Language-Action Models
ID: 2603.01766
Authors: Haoyun Liu, Jianzhuang Zhao, Xinyuan Chang et al.
Date: 2026-03-02
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Despite the rapid progress of Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models, the prevailing paradigm of predicting discrete waypoints remains fundamentally misaligned with the intrinsic continuity of physical m...

=== 30 ===
Title: From One-to-One to Many-to-Many: Dynamic Cross-Layer Injection for Deep Vision-Language Fusion
ID: 2601.10710
Authors: Cheng Chen, Yuyu Guo, Pengpeng Zeng et al.
Date: 2026-01-15
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) create a severe visual feature bottleneck by using a crude, asymmetric connection that links only the output of the vision encoder to the input of the large language mode...

=== 31 ===
Title: LAP: Language-Action Pre-Training Enables Zero-shot Cross-Embodiment Transfer
ID: 2602.10556
Authors: Lihan Zha, Asher J. Hancock, Mingtong Zhang et al.
Date: 2026-02-11
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: A long-standing goal in robotics is a generalist policy that can be deployed zero-shot on new robot embodiments without per-embodiment adaptation. Despite large-scale multi-embodiment pre-training, ex...

=== 32 ===
Title: KnowVal: A Knowledge-Augmented and Value-Guided Autonomous Driving System
ID: 2512.20299
Authors: Zhongyu Xia, Wenhao Chen, Yongtao Wang et al.
Date: 2025-12-23
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV
Abstract: Visual-language reasoning, driving knowledge, and value alignment are essential for advanced autonomous driving systems. However, existing approaches largely rely on data-driven learning, making it di...

=== 33 ===
Title: Modular Safety Guardrails Are Necessary for Foundation-Model-Enabled Robots in the Real World
ID: 2602.04056
Authors: Joonkyung Kim, Wenxi Chen, Davood Soleymanzadeh et al.
Date: 2026-02-03
Categories: eess.SY, cs.RO
Abstract: The integration of foundation models (FMs) into robotics has accelerated real-world deployment, while introducing new safety challenges arising from open-ended semantic reasoning and embodied physical...

=== 34 ===
Title: Safe-SDL:Establishing Safety Boundaries and Control Mechanisms for AI-Driven Self-Driving Laboratories
ID: 2602.15061
Authors: Zihan Zhang, Haohui Que, Junhan Chang et al.
Date: 2026-02-13
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: The emergence of Self-Driving Laboratories (SDLs) transforms scientific discovery methodology by integrating AI with robotic automation to create closed-loop experimental systems capable of autonomous...

=== 35 ===
Title: LaST$_{0}$: Latent Spatio-Temporal Chain-of-Thought for Robotic Vision-Language-Action Model
ID: 2601.05248
Authors: Zhuoyang Liu, Jiaming Liu, Hao Chen et al.
Date: 2026-01-08
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models have recently shown strong generalization, with some approaches seeking to explicitly generate linguistic reasoning traces or predict future observations prior to e...

=== 36 ===
Title: VideoAuto-R1: Video Auto Reasoning via Thinking Once, Answering Twice
ID: 2601.05175
Authors: Shuming Liu, Mingchen Zhuge, Changsheng Zhao et al.
Date: 2026-01-08
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning has emerged as a powerful tool for multimodal large language models on video understanding tasks. However, its necessity and advantages over direct answering remain un...

=== 37 ===
Title: From Representational Complementarity to Dual Systems: Synergizing VLM and Vision-Only Backbones for End-to-End Driving
ID: 2602.10719
Authors: Sining Ang, Yuguang Yang, Chenxu Dang et al.
Date: 2026-02-11
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CV
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) driving augments end-to-end (E2E) planning with language-enabled backbones, yet it remains unclear what changes beyond the usual accuracy--cost trade-off. We revisit this ...

=== 38 ===
Title: E3AD: An Emotion-Aware Vision-Language-Action Model for Human-Centric End-to-End Autonomous Driving
ID: 2512.04733
Authors: Yihong Tang, Haicheng Liao, Tong Nie et al.
Date: 2025-12-04
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: End-to-end autonomous driving (AD) systems increasingly adopt vision-language-action (VLA) models, yet they typically ignore the passenger's emotional state, which is central to comfort and AD accepta...

=== 39 ===
Title: VL-JEPA: Joint Embedding Predictive Architecture for Vision-language
ID: 2512.10942
Authors: Delong Chen, Mustafa Shukor, Theo Moutakanni et al.
Date: 2025-12-11
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: We introduce VL-JEPA, a vision-language model built on a Joint Embedding Predictive Architecture (JEPA). Instead of autoregressively generating tokens as in classical VLMs, VL-JEPA predicts continuous...

=== 40 ===
Title: Mull-Tokens: Modality-Agnostic Latent Thinking
ID: 2512.10941
Authors: Arijit Ray, Ahmed Abdelkader, Chengzhi Mao et al.
Date: 2025-12-11
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: Reasoning goes beyond language; the real world requires reasoning about space, time, affordances, and much more that words alone cannot convey. Existing multimodal models exploring the potential of re...

=== 41 ===
Title: Action Hallucination in Generative Visual-Language-Action Models
ID: 2602.06339
Authors: Harold Soh, Eugene Lim
Date: 2026-02-06
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: Robot Foundation Models such as Vision-Language-Action models are rapidly reshaping how robot policies are trained and deployed, replacing hand-designed planners with end-to-end generative action mode...

=== 42 ===
Title: Reliable and Responsible Foundation Models: A Comprehensive Survey
ID: 2602.08145
Authors: Xinyu Yang, Junlin Han, Rishi Bommasani et al.
Date: 2026-02-04
Categories: cs.LG, cs.AI, cs.CL, cs.CV, cs.CY
Abstract: Foundation models, including Large Language Models (LLMs), Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs), Image Generative Models (i.e, Text-to-Image Models and Image-Editing Models), and Video Generative ...

=== 43 ===
Title: Driving with A Thousand Faces: A Benchmark for Closed-Loop Personalized End-to-End Autonomous Driving
ID: 2602.18757
Authors: Xiaoru Dong, Ruiqin Li, Xiao Han et al.
Date: 2026-02-21
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Human driving behavior is inherently diverse, yet most end-to-end autonomous driving (E2E-AD) systems learn a single average driving style, neglecting individual differences. Achieving personalized E2...

=== 44 ===
Title: Forging Spatial Intelligence: A Roadmap of Multi-Modal Data Pre-Training for Autonomous Systems
ID: 2512.24385
Authors: Song Wang, Lingdong Kong, Xiaolu Liu et al.
Date: 2025-12-30
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: The rapid advancement of autonomous systems, including self-driving vehicles and drones, has intensified the need to forge true Spatial Intelligence from multi-modal onboard sensor data. While foundat...

=== 45 ===
Title: Are All Data Necessary? Efficient Data Pruning for Large-scale Autonomous Driving Dataset via Trajectory Entropy Maximization
ID: 2512.19270
Authors: Zhaoyang Liu, Weitao Zhou, Junze Wen et al.
Date: 2025-12-22
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Collecting large-scale naturalistic driving data is essential for training robust autonomous driving planners. However, real-world datasets often contain a substantial amount of repetitive and low-val...

=== 46 ===
Title: InternData-A1: Pioneering High-Fidelity Synthetic Data for Pre-training Generalist Policy
ID: 2511.16651
Authors: Yang Tian, Yuyin Yang, Yiman Xie et al.
Date: 2025-11-20
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Recent works explore how real and synthetic data contribute to Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models' generalization. While current VLA models have shown the strong effectiveness of large-scale real-rob...

=== 47 ===
Title: Alpamayo-R1: Bridging Reasoning and Action Prediction for Generalizable Autonomous Driving in the Long Tail
ID: 2511.00088
Authors: NVIDIA, :, Yan Wang et al.
Date: 2025-10-30
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.LG
Abstract: End-to-end architectures trained via imitation learning have advanced autonomous driving by scaling model size and data, yet performance remains brittle in safety-critical long-tail scenarios where su...

=== 48 ===
Title: Risk-Aware World Model Predictive Control for Generalizable End-to-End Autonomous Driving
ID: 2602.23259
Authors: Jiangxin Sun, Feng Xue, Teng Long et al.
Date: 2026-02-26
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.RO
Abstract: With advances in imitation learning (IL) and large-scale driving datasets, end-to-end autonomous driving (E2E-AD) has made great progress recently. Currently, IL-based methods have become a mainstream...

=== 49 ===
Title: World Guidance: World Modeling in Condition Space for Action Generation
ID: 2602.22010
Authors: Yue Su, Sijin Chen, Haixin Shi et al.
Date: 2026-02-25
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CV
Abstract: Leveraging future observation modeling to facilitate action generation presents a promising avenue for enhancing the capabilities of Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models. However, existing approaches s...

=== 50 ===
Title: GigaBrain-0.5M*: a VLA That Learns From World Model-Based Reinforcement Learning
ID: 2602.12099
Authors: GigaBrain Team, Boyuan Wang, Bohan Li et al.
Date: 2026-02-12
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Vision-language-action (VLA) models that directly predict multi-step action chunks from current observations face inherent limitations due to constrained scene understanding and weak future anticipati...

=== 51 ===
Title: SAGE: Scalable Agentic 3D Scene Generation for Embodied AI
ID: 2602.10116
Authors: Hongchi Xia, Xuan Li, Zhaoshuo Li et al.
Date: 2026-02-10
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: Real-world data collection for embodied agents remains costly and unsafe, calling for scalable, realistic, and simulator-ready 3D environments. However, existing scene-generation systems often rely on...

=== 52 ===
Title: WorldArena: A Unified Benchmark for Evaluating Perception and Functional Utility of Embodied World Models
ID: 2602.08971
Authors: Yu Shang, Zhuohang Li, Yiding Ma et al.
Date: 2026-02-09
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: While world models have emerged as a cornerstone of embodied intelligence by enabling agents to reason about environmental dynamics through action-conditioned prediction, their evaluation remains frag...

=== 53 ===
Title: DreamDojo: A Generalist Robot World Model from Large-Scale Human Videos
ID: 2602.06949
Authors: Shenyuan Gao, William Liang, Kaiyuan Zheng et al.
Date: 2026-02-06
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV, cs.LG
Abstract: Being able to simulate the outcomes of actions in varied environments will revolutionize the development of generalist agents at scale. However, modeling these world dynamics, especially for dexterous...

=== 54 ===
Title: World-VLA-Loop: Closed-Loop Learning of Video World Model and VLA Policy
ID: 2602.06508
Authors: Xiaokang Liu, Zechen Bai, Hai Ci et al.
Date: 2026-02-06
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Recent progress in robotic world models has leveraged video diffusion transformers to predict future observations conditioned on historical states and actions. While these models can simulate realisti...

=== 55 ===
Title: Video Generation Models in Robotics -- Applications, Research Challenges, Future Directions
ID: 2601.07823
Authors: Zhiting Mei, Tenny Yin, Ola Shorinwa et al.
Date: 2026-01-12
Categories: eess.SY, cs.RO
Abstract: Video generation models have emerged as high-fidelity models of the physical world, capable of synthesizing high-quality videos capturing fine-grained interactions between agents and their environment...

=== 56 ===
Title: A Comprehensive Survey on World Models for Embodied AI
ID: 2510.16732
Authors: Xinqing Li, Xin He, Le Zhang et al.
Date: 2025-10-19
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Embodied AI requires agents that perceive, act, and anticipate how actions reshape future world states. World models serve as internal simulators that capture environment dynamics, enabling forward an...

=== 57 ===
Title: RynnVLA-002: A Unified Vision-Language-Action and World Model
ID: 2511.17502
Authors: Jun Cen, Siteng Huang, Yuqian Yuan et al.
Date: 2025-11-21
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: We introduce RynnVLA-002, a unified Vision-Language-Action (VLA) and world model. The world model leverages action and visual inputs to predict future image states, learning the underlying physics of ...

=== 58 ===
Title: ManualVLA: A Unified VLA Model for Chain-of-Thought Manual Generation and Robotic Manipulation
ID: 2512.02013
Authors: Chenyang Gu, Jiaming Liu, Hao Chen et al.
Date: 2025-12-01
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models have recently emerged, demonstrating strong generalization in robotic scene understanding and manipulation. However, when confronted with long-horizon tasks that re...

=== 59 ===
Title: Stag-1: Towards Realistic 4D Driving Simulation with Video Generation Model
ID: 2412.05280
Authors: Lening Wang, Wenzhao Zheng, Dalong Du et al.
Date: 2024-12-06
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.LG
Abstract: 4D driving simulation is essential for developing realistic autonomous driving simulators. Despite advancements in existing methods for generating driving scenes, significant challenges remain in view...

=== 60 ===
Title: SIMA 2: A Generalist Embodied Agent for Virtual Worlds
ID: 2512.04797
Authors: SIMA team, Adrian Bolton, Alexander Lerchner et al.
Date: 2025-12-04
Categories: cs.AI, cs.RO
Abstract: We introduce SIMA 2, a generalist embodied agent that understands and acts in a wide variety of 3D virtual worlds. Built upon a Gemini foundation model, SIMA 2 represents a significant step toward act...

=== 61 ===
Title: VFMF: World Modeling by Forecasting Vision Foundation Model Features
ID: 2512.11225
Authors: Gabrijel Boduljak, Yushi Lan, Christian Rupprecht et al.
Date: 2025-12-12
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.LG
Abstract: Forecasting from partial observations is central to world modeling. Many recent methods represent the world through images, and reduce forecasting to stochastic video generation. Although such methods...

=== 62 ===
Title: DiST-4D: Disentangled Spatiotemporal Diffusion with Metric Depth for 4D Driving Scene Generation
ID: 2503.15208
Authors: Jiazhe Guo, Yikang Ding, Xiwu Chen et al.
Date: 2025-03-19
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Current generative models struggle to synthesize dynamic 4D driving scenes that simultaneously support temporal extrapolation and spatial novel view synthesis (NVS) without per-scene optimization. A k...

=== 63 ===
Title: Real Deep Research for AI, Robotics and Beyond
ID: 2510.20809
Authors: Xueyan Zou, Jianglong Ye, Hao Zhang et al.
Date: 2025-10-23
Categories: cs.AI, cs.CL, cs.CV, cs.LG
Abstract: With the rapid growth of research in AI and robotics now producing over 10,000 papers annually it has become increasingly difficult for researchers to stay up to date. Fast evolving trends, the rise o...

=== 64 ===
Title: Scalable Vision-Language-Action Model Pretraining for Robotic Manipulation with Real-Life Human Activity Videos
ID: 2510.21571
Authors: Qixiu Li, Yu Deng, Yaobo Liang et al.
Date: 2025-10-24
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV, cs.LG
Abstract: This paper presents a novel approach for pretraining robotic manipulation Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models using a large corpus of unscripted real-life video recordings of human hand activities. Tr...

=== 65 ===
Title: TraceGen: World Modeling in 3D Trace Space Enables Learning from Cross-Embodiment Videos
ID: 2511.21690
Authors: Seungjae Lee, Yoonkyo Jung, Inkook Chun et al.
Date: 2025-11-26
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CV, cs.LG
Abstract: Learning new robot tasks on new platforms and in new scenes from only a handful of demonstrations remains challenging. While videos of other embodiments - humans and different robots - are abundant, d...

=== 66 ===
Title: How Do VLAs Effectively Inherit from VLMs?
ID: 2511.06619
Authors: Chuheng Zhang, Rushuai Yang, Xiaoyu Chen et al.
Date: 2025-11-10
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: Vision-language-action (VLA) models hold the promise to attain generalizable embodied control. To achieve this, a pervasive paradigm is to leverage the rich vision-semantic priors of large vision-lang...

=== 67 ===
Title: LDA-1B: Scaling Latent Dynamics Action Model via Universal Embodied Data Ingestion
ID: 2602.12215
Authors: Jiangran Lyu, Kai Liu, Xuheng Zhang et al.
Date: 2026-02-12
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Recent robot foundation models largely rely on large-scale behavior cloning, which imitates expert actions but discards transferable dynamics knowledge embedded in heterogeneous embodied data. While t...

=== 68 ===
Title: PixelRefer: A Unified Framework for Spatio-Temporal Object Referring with Arbitrary Granularity
ID: 2510.23603
Authors: Yuqian Yuan, Wenqiao Zhang, Xin Li et al.
Date: 2025-10-27
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have demonstrated strong general-purpose capabilities in open-world visual comprehension. However, most existing MLLMs primarily focus on holistic, scene-level...

=== 69 ===
Title: ZTRS: Zero-Imitation End-to-end Autonomous Driving with Trajectory Scoring
ID: 2510.24108
Authors: Zhenxin Li, Wenhao Yao, Zi Wang et al.
Date: 2025-10-28
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CV
Abstract: End-to-end autonomous driving maps raw sensor inputs directly into ego-vehicle trajectories to avoid cascading errors from perception modules and to leverage rich semantic cues. Existing frameworks la...

=== 70 ===
Title: Unified Reinforcement and Imitation Learning for Vision-Language Models
ID: 2510.19307
Authors: Byung-Kwan Lee, Ryo Hachiuma, Yong Man Ro et al.
Date: 2025-10-22
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have achieved remarkable progress, yet their large scale often renders them impractical for resource-constrained environments. This paper introduces Unified Reinforcement...

=== 71 ===
Title: SRPO: Self-Referential Policy Optimization for Vision-Language-Action Models
ID: 2511.15605
Authors: Senyu Fei, Siyin Wang, Li Ji et al.
Date: 2025-11-19
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CL, cs.CV
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models excel in robotic manipulation but are constrained by their heavy reliance on expert demonstrations, leading to demonstration bias and limiting performance. Reinforc...

=== 72 ===
Title: NORA-1.5: A Vision-Language-Action Model Trained using World Model- and Action-based Preference Rewards
ID: 2511.14659
Authors: Chia-Yu Hung, Navonil Majumder, Haoyuan Deng et al.
Date: 2025-11-18
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: Vision--language--action (VLA) models have recently shown promising performance on a variety of embodied tasks, yet they still fall short in reliability and generalization, especially when deployed ac...

=== 73 ===
Title: WMPO: World Model-based Policy Optimization for Vision-Language-Action Models
ID: N/A
Authors: 
Date: 
Categories: 
Abstract: ...

=== 74 ===
Title: MindGPT-4ov: An Enhanced MLLM via a Multi-Stage Post-Training Paradigm
ID: 2512.02895
Authors: Wei Chen, Chaoqun Du, Feng Gu et al.
Date: 2025-12-02
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: We present MindGPT-4ov, a multimodal large language model (MLLM) that introduces a general post-training paradigm spanning data production, model training, and efficient deployment. It achieves state-...

=== 75 ===
Title: Reinforcing Action Policies by Prophesying
ID: 2511.20633
Authors: Jiahui Zhang, Ze Huang, Chun Gu et al.
Date: 2025-11-25
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) policies excel in aligning language, perception, and robot control. However, most VLAs are trained purely by imitation, which overfits to demonstrations, and is brittle un...

=== 76 ===
Title: $π_\texttt{RL}$: Online RL Fine-tuning for Flow-based Vision-Language-Action Models
ID: 2510.25889
Authors: Kang Chen, Zhihao Liu, Tonghe Zhang et al.
Date: 2025-10-29
Categories: cs.LG
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models enable robots to understand and perform complex tasks from multimodal input. Although recent work explores using reinforcement learning (RL) to automate the laborio...

=== 77 ===
Title: ReCogDrive: A Reinforced Cognitive Framework for End-to-End Autonomous Driving
ID: 2506.08052
Authors: Yongkang Li, Kaixin Xiong, Xiangyu Guo et al.
Date: 2025-06-09
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: Recent studies have explored leveraging the world knowledge and cognitive capabilities of Vision-Language Models (VLMs) to address the long-tail problem in end-to-end autonomous driving. However, exis...

=== 78 ===
Title: RoboScape-R: Unified Reward-Observation World Models for Generalizable Robotics Training via RL
ID: 2512.03556
Authors: Yinzhou Tang, Yu Shang, Yinuo Chen et al.
Date: 2025-12-03
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CV
Abstract: Achieving generalizable embodied policies remains a key challenge. Traditional policy learning paradigms, including both Imitation Learning (IL) and Reinforcement Learning (RL), struggle to cultivate ...

=== 79 ===
Title: Alleviating Sparse Rewards by Modeling Step-Wise and Long-Term Sampling Effects in Flow-Based GRPO
ID: 2602.06422
Authors: Yunze Tong, Mushui Liu, Canyu Zhao et al.
Date: 2026-02-06
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Deploying GRPO on Flow Matching models has proven effective for text-to-image generation. However, existing paradigms typically propagate an outcome-based reward to all preceding denoising steps witho...

=== 80 ===
Title: PhyCritic: Multimodal Critic Models for Physical AI
ID: 2602.11124
Authors: Tianyi Xiong, Shihao Wang, Guilin Liu et al.
Date: 2026-02-11
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: With the rapid development of large multimodal models, reliable judge and critic models have become essential for open-ended evaluation and preference alignment, providing pairwise preferences, numeri...

=== 81 ===
Title: PhyBlock: A Progressive Benchmark for Physical Understanding and Planning via 3D Block Assembly
ID: 2506.08708
Authors: Liang Ma, Jiajun Wen, Min Lin et al.
Date: 2025-06-10
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV
Abstract: While vision-language models (VLMs) have demonstrated promising capabilities in reasoning and planning for embodied agents, their ability to comprehend physical phenomena, particularly within structur...

=== 82 ===
Title: Beyond VLM-Based Rewards: Diffusion-Native Latent Reward Modeling
ID: 2602.11146
Authors: Gongye Liu, Bo Yang, Yida Zhi et al.
Date: 2026-02-11
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: Preference optimization for diffusion and flow-matching models relies on reward functions that are both discriminatively robust and computationally efficient. Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have emerge...

=== 83 ===
Title: RISE: Self-Improving Robot Policy with Compositional World Model
ID: 2602.11075
Authors: Jiazhi Yang, Kunyang Lin, Jinwei Li et al.
Date: 2026-02-11
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Despite the sustained scaling on model capacity and data acquisition, Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models remain brittle in contact-rich and dynamic manipulation tasks, where minor execution deviation...

=== 84 ===
Title: VLAW: Iterative Co-Improvement of Vision-Language-Action Policy and World Model
ID: 2602.12063
Authors: Yanjiang Guo, Tony Lee, Lucy Xiaoyang Shi et al.
Date: 2026-02-12
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: The goal of this paper is to improve the performance and reliability of vision-language-action (VLA) models through iterative online interaction. Since collecting policy rollouts in the real world is ...

=== 85 ===
Title: WoVR: World Models as Reliable Simulators for Post-Training VLA Policies with RL
ID: 2602.13977
Authors: Zhennan Jiang, Shangqing Zhou, Yutong Jiang et al.
Date: 2026-02-15
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI
Abstract: Reinforcement learning (RL) promises to unlock capabilities beyond imitation learning for Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models, but its requirement for massive real-world interaction prevents direct de...

=== 86 ===
Title: A Survey on Efficient Vision-Language-Action Models
ID: 2510.24795
Authors: Zhaoshu Yu, Bo Wang, Pengpeng Zeng et al.
Date: 2025-10-27
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.LG, cs.RO
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action models (VLAs) represent a significant frontier in embodied intelligence, aiming to bridge digital knowledge with physical-world interaction. Despite their remarkable performance...

=== 87 ===
Title: LightFusion: A Light-weighted, Double Fusion Framework for Unified Multimodal Understanding and Generation
ID: 2510.22946
Authors: Zeyu Wang, Zilong Chen, Chenhui Gou et al.
Date: 2025-10-27
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Unified multimodal models have recently shown remarkable gains in both capability and versatility, yet most leading systems are still trained from scratch and require substantial computational resourc...

=== 88 ===
Title: Efficient Multi-Camera Tokenization with Triplanes for End-to-End Driving
ID: 2506.12251
Authors: Boris Ivanovic, Cristiano Saltori, Yurong You et al.
Date: 2025-06-13
Categories: cs.CV, cs.LG, cs.RO
Abstract: Autoregressive Transformers are increasingly being deployed as end-to-end robot and autonomous vehicle (AV) policy architectures, owing to their scalability and potential to leverage internet-scale pr...

=== 89 ===
Title: PSA: Pyramid Sparse Attention for Efficient Video Understanding and Generation
ID: 2512.04025
Authors: Xiaolong Li, Youping Gu, Xi Lin et al.
Date: 2025-12-03
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.LG
Abstract: Attention mechanisms are the core of foundation models, but their quadratic complexity remains a critical bottleneck for scaling. This challenge has driven the development of efficient attention mecha...

=== 90 ===
Title: FASTer: Toward Efficient Autoregressive Vision Language Action Modeling via Neural Action Tokenization
ID: 2512.04952
Authors: Yicheng Liu, Shiduo Zhang, Zibin Dong et al.
Date: 2025-12-04
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: Autoregressive vision-language-action (VLA) models have recently demonstrated strong capabilities in robotic manipulation. However, their core process of action tokenization often involves a trade-off...

=== 91 ===
Title: TrajMoE: Scene-Adaptive Trajectory Planning with Mixture of Experts and Reinforcement Learning
ID: 2512.07135
Authors: Zebin Xing, Pengxuan Yang, Linbo Wang et al.
Date: 2025-12-08
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: Current autonomous driving systems often favor end-to-end frameworks, which take sensor inputs like images and learn to map them into trajectory space via neural networks. Previous work has demonstrat...

=== 92 ===
Title: Blink: Dynamic Visual Token Resolution for Enhanced Multimodal Understanding
ID: 2512.10548
Authors: Yuchen Feng, Zhenyu Zhang, Naibin Gu et al.
Date: 2025-12-11
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have achieved remarkable progress on various vision-language tasks, yet their visual perception remains limited. Humans, in comparison, perceive complex scenes...

=== 93 ===
Title: Towards Efficient and Effective Multi-Camera Encoding for End-to-End Driving
ID: 2512.10947
Authors: Jiawei Yang, Ziyu Chen, Yurong You et al.
Date: 2025-12-11
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: We present Flex, an efficient and effective scene encoder that addresses the computational bottleneck of processing high-volume multi-camera data in end-to-end autonomous driving. Flex employs a small...

=== 94 ===
Title: AstraNav-Memory: Contexts Compression for Long Memory
ID: 2512.21627
Authors: Botao Ren, Junjun Hu, Xinda Xue et al.
Date: 2025-12-25
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Lifelong embodied navigation requires agents to accumulate, retain, and exploit spatial-semantic experience across tasks, enabling efficient exploration in novel environments and rapid goal reaching i...

=== 95 ===
Title: DeepSeek-OCR 2: Visual Causal Flow
ID: 2601.20552
Authors: Haoran Wei, Yaofeng Sun, Yukun Li
Date: 2026-01-28
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: We present DeepSeek-OCR 2 to investigate the feasibility of a novel encoder-DeepEncoder V2-capable of dynamically reordering visual tokens upon image semantics. Conventional vision-language models (VL...

=== 96 ===
Title: ApET: Approximation-Error Guided Token Compression for Efficient VLMs
ID: 2602.19870
Authors: Qiankun Ma, Ziyao Zhang, Haofei Wang et al.
Date: 2026-02-23
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Recent Vision-Language Models (VLMs) have demonstrated remarkable multimodal understanding capabilities, yet the redundant visual tokens incur prohibitive computational overhead and degrade inference ...

=== 97 ===
Title: How Fast Can I Run My VLA? Demystifying VLA Inference Performance with VLA-Perf
ID: 2602.18397
Authors: Wenqi Jiang, Jason Clemons, Karu Sankaralingam et al.
Date: 2026-02-20
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models have recently demonstrated impressive capabilities across various embodied AI tasks. While deploying VLA models on real-world robots imposes strict real-time infere...

=== 98 ===
Title: BagelVLA: Enhancing Long-Horizon Manipulation via Interleaved Vision-Language-Action Generation
ID: 2602.09849
Authors: Yucheng Hu, Jianke Zhang, Yuanfei Luo et al.
Date: 2026-02-10
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Equipping embodied agents with the ability to reason about tasks, foresee physical outcomes, and generate precise actions is essential for general-purpose manipulation. While recent Vision-Language-Ac...

=== 99 ===
Title: AlignDrive: Aligned Lateral-Longitudinal Planning for End-to-End Autonomous Driving
ID: 2601.01762
Authors: Yanhao Wu, Haoyang Zhang, Fei He et al.
Date: 2026-01-05
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CV
Abstract: End-to-end autonomous driving has rapidly progressed, enabling joint perception and planning in complex environments. In the planning stage, state-of-the-art (SOTA) end-to-end autonomous driving model...

=== 100 ===
Title: RoboMIND 2.0: A Multimodal, Bimanual Mobile Manipulation Dataset for Generalizable Embodied Intelligence
ID: 2512.24653
Authors: Chengkai Hou, Kun Wu, Jiaming Liu et al.
Date: 2025-12-31
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: While data-driven imitation learning has revolutionized robotic manipulation, current approaches remain constrained by the scarcity of large-scale, diverse real-world demonstrations. Consequently, the...

=== 101 ===
Title: DriveLaW:Unifying Planning and Video Generation in a Latent Driving World
ID: 2512.23421
Authors: Tianze Xia, Yongkang Li, Lijun Zhou et al.
Date: 2025-12-29
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: World models have become crucial for autonomous driving, as they learn how scenarios evolve over time to address the long-tail challenges of the real world. However, current approaches relegate world ...

=== 102 ===
Title: MiMo-Embodied: X-Embodied Foundation Model Technical Report
ID: 2511.16518
Authors: Xiaoshuai Hao, Lei Zhou, Zhijian Huang et al.
Date: 2025-11-20
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CL, cs.CV
Abstract: We open-source MiMo-Embodied, the first cross-embodied foundation model to successfully integrate and achieve state-of-the-art performance in both Autonomous Driving and Embodied AI. MiMo-Embodied set...

=== 103 ===
Title: $π^{*}_{0.6}$: a VLA That Learns From Experience
ID: 2511.14759
Authors: Physical Intelligence, Ali Amin, Raichelle Aniceto et al.
Date: 2025-11-18
Categories: cs.LG, cs.RO
Abstract: We study how vision-language-action (VLA) models can improve through real-world deployments via reinforcement learning (RL). We present a general-purpose method, RL with Experience and Corrections via...

=== 104 ===
Title: SimScale: Learning to Drive via Real-World Simulation at Scale
ID: 2511.23369
Authors: Haochen Tian, Tianyu Li, Haochen Liu et al.
Date: 2025-11-28
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: Achieving fully autonomous driving systems requires learning rational decisions in a wide span of scenarios, including safety-critical and out-of-distribution ones. However, such cases are underrepres...

=== 105 ===
Title: HybridWorldSim: A Scalable and Controllable High-fidelity Simulator for Autonomous Driving
ID: 2511.22187
Authors: Qiang Li, Yingwenqi Jiang, Tuoxi Li et al.
Date: 2025-11-27
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: Realistic and controllable simulation is critical for advancing end-to-end autonomous driving, yet existing approaches often struggle to support novel view synthesis under large viewpoint changes or t...

=== 106 ===
Title: UniUGP: Unifying Understanding, Generation, and Planing For End-to-end Autonomous Driving
ID: 2512.09864
Authors: Hao Lu, Ziyang Liu, Guangfeng Jiang et al.
Date: 2025-12-10
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Autonomous driving (AD) systems struggle in long-tail scenarios due to limited world knowledge and weak visual dynamic modeling. Existing vision-language-action (VLA)-based methods cannot leverage unl...

=== 107 ===
Title: MindDrive: A Vision-Language-Action Model for Autonomous Driving via Online Reinforcement Learning
ID: 2512.13636
Authors: Haoyu Fu, Diankun Zhang, Zongchuang Zhao et al.
Date: 2025-12-15
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: Current Vision-Language-Action (VLA) paradigms in autonomous driving primarily rely on Imitation Learning (IL), which introduces inherent challenges such as distribution shift and causal confusion. On...

=== 108 ===
Title: WAM-Flow: Parallel Coarse-to-Fine Motion Planning via Discrete Flow Matching for Autonomous Driving
ID: 2512.06112
Authors: Yifang Xu, Jiahao Cui, Feipeng Cai et al.
Date: 2025-12-05
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.CV
Abstract: We introduce WAM-Flow, a vision-language-action (VLA) model that casts ego-trajectory planning as discrete flow matching over a structured token space. In contrast to autoregressive decoders, WAM-Flow...

=== 109 ===
Title: Motus: A Unified Latent Action World Model
ID: 2512.13030
Authors: Hongzhe Bi, Hengkai Tan, Shenghao Xie et al.
Date: 2025-12-15
Categories: cs.CV, cs.LG, cs.RO
Abstract: While a general embodied agent must function as a unified system, current methods are built on isolated models for understanding, world modeling, and control. This fragmentation prevents unifying mult...

=== 110 ===
Title: DrivePI: Spatial-aware 4D MLLM for Unified Autonomous Driving Understanding, Perception, Prediction and Planning
ID: 2512.12799
Authors: Zhe Liu, Runhui Huang, Rui Yang et al.
Date: 2025-12-14
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Although multi-modal large language models (MLLMs) have shown strong capabilities across diverse domains, their application in generating fine-grained 3D perception and prediction outputs in autonomou...

=== 111 ===
Title: ABot-M0: VLA Foundation Model for Robotic Manipulation with Action Manifold Learning
ID: 2602.11236
Authors: Yandan Yang, Shuang Zeng, Tong Lin et al.
Date: 2026-02-11
Categories: cs.CV, cs.CL, cs.RO
Abstract: Building general-purpose embodied agents across diverse hardware remains a central challenge in robotics, often framed as the ''one-brain, many-forms'' paradigm. Progress is hindered by fragmented dat...

=== 112 ===
Title: Xiaomi-Robotics-0: An Open-Sourced Vision-Language-Action Model with Real-Time Execution
ID: 2602.12684
Authors: Rui Cai, Jun Guo, Xinze He et al.
Date: 2026-02-13
Categories: cs.RO, cs.LG
Abstract: In this report, we introduce Xiaomi-Robotics-0, an advanced vision-language-action (VLA) model optimized for high performance and fast and smooth real-time execution. The key to our method lies in a c...

=== 113 ===
Title: RynnBrain: Open Embodied Foundation Models
ID: 2602.14979
Authors: Ronghao Dang, Jiayan Guo, Bohan Hou et al.
Date: 2026-02-13
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Despite rapid progress in multimodal foundation models, embodied intelligence community still lacks a unified, physically grounded foundation model that integrates perception, reasoning, and planning ...

=== 114 ===
Title: DM0: An Embodied-Native Vision-Language-Action Model towards Physical AI
ID: 2602.14974
Authors: En Yu, Haoran Lv, Jianjian Sun et al.
Date: 2026-02-16
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Moving beyond the traditional paradigm of adapting internet-pretrained models to physical tasks, we present DM0, an Embodied-Native Vision-Language-Action (VLA) framework designed for Physical AI. Unl...

=== 115 ===
Title: HiST-VLA: A Hierarchical Spatio-Temporal Vision-Language-Action Model for End-to-End Autonomous Driving
ID: 2602.13329
Authors: Yiru Wang, Zichong Gu, Yu Gao et al.
Date: 2026-02-11
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.RO
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models offer promising capabilities for autonomous driving through multimodal understanding. However, their utilization in safety-critical scenarios is constrained by inhe...

=== 116 ===
Title: World Action Models are Zero-shot Policies
ID: 2602.15922
Authors: Seonghyeon Ye, Yunhao Ge, Kaiyuan Zheng et al.
Date: 2026-02-17
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CV, cs.LG
Abstract: State-of-the-art Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models excel at semantic generalization but struggle to generalize to unseen physical motions in novel environments. We introduce DreamZero, a World Actio...

=== 117 ===
Title: HALO: A Unified Vision-Language-Action Model for Embodied Multimodal Chain-of-Thought Reasoning
ID: 2602.21157
Authors: Quanxin Shou, Fangqi Zhu, Shawn Chen et al.
Date: 2026-02-24
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models have shown strong performance in robotic manipulation, but often struggle in long-horizon or out-of-distribution scenarios due to the lack of explicit mechanisms fo...

=== 118 ===
Title: Unleashing the Potential of Diffusion Models for End-to-End Autonomous Driving
ID: 2602.22801
Authors: Yinan Zheng, Tianyi Tan, Bin Huang et al.
Date: 2026-02-26
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.LG
Abstract: Diffusion models have become a popular choice for decision-making tasks in robotics, and more recently, are also being considered for solving autonomous driving tasks. However, their applications and ...

=== 119 ===
Title: F1: A Vision-Language-Action Model Bridging Understanding and Generation to Actions
ID: 2509.06951
Authors: Qi Lv, Weijie Kong, Hao Li et al.
Date: 2025-09-08
Categories: cs.RO, cs.CV
Abstract: Executing language-conditioned tasks in dynamic visual environments remains a central challenge in embodied AI. Existing Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models predominantly adopt reactive state-to-actio...

=== 120 ===
Title: Emerging Properties in Unified Multimodal Pretraining
ID: 2505.14683
Authors: Chaorui Deng, Deyao Zhu, Kunchang Li et al.
Date: 2025-05-20
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Unifying multimodal understanding and generation has shown impressive capabilities in cutting-edge proprietary systems. In this work, we introduce BAGEL, an open-source foundational model that nativel...

=== 121 ===
Title: AsyncVLA: Asynchronous Flow Matching for Vision-Language-Action Models
ID: 2511.14148
Authors: Yuhua Jiang, Shuang Cheng, Yan Ding et al.
Date: 2025-11-18
Categories: cs.RO, cs.AI, cs.LG
Abstract: Vision-language-action (VLA) models have recently emerged as a powerful paradigm for building generalist robots. However, traditional VLA models that generate actions through flow matching (FM) typica...

=== 122 ===
Title: Efficient Training of Diffusion Mixture-of-Experts Models: A Practical Recipe
ID: 2512.01252
Authors: Yahui Liu, Yang Yue, Jingyuan Zhang et al.
Date: 2025-12-01
Categories: cs.LG, cs.CV
Abstract: Recent efforts on Diffusion Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) models have primarily focused on developing more sophisticated routing mechanisms. However, we observe that the underlying architectural configurat...

=== 123 ===
Title: SwimBird: Eliciting Switchable Reasoning Mode in Hybrid Autoregressive MLLMs
ID: 2602.06040
Authors: Jintao Tong, Shilin Yan, Hongwei Xue et al.
Date: 2026-02-05
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have made remarkable progress in multimodal perception and reasoning by bridging vision and language. However, most existing MLLMs perform reasoning primarily ...

=== 124 ===
Title: Chain-of-Visual-Thought: Teaching VLMs to See and Think Better with Continuous Visual Tokens
ID: 2511.19418
Authors: Yiming Qin, Bomin Wei, Jiaxin Ge et al.
Date: 2025-11-24
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.LG
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) excel at reasoning in linguistic space but struggle with perceptual understanding that requires dense visual perception, e.g., spatial reasoning and geometric awareness. ...

=== 125 ===
Title: Qwen3-VL Technical Report
ID: 2511.21631
Authors: Shuai Bai, Yuxuan Cai, Ruizhe Chen et al.
Date: 2025-11-26
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: We introduce Qwen3-VL, the most capable vision-language model in the Qwen series to date, achieving superior performance across a broad range of multimodal benchmarks. It natively supports interleaved...

=== 126 ===
Title: SAM 3D: 3Dfy Anything in Images
ID: 2511.16624
Authors: SAM 3D Team, Xingyu Chen, Fu-Jen Chu et al.
Date: 2025-11-20
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: We present SAM 3D, a generative model for visually grounded 3D object reconstruction, predicting geometry, texture, and layout from a single image. SAM 3D excels in natural images, where occlusion and...

=== 127 ===
Title: Rethinking generative image pretraining: How far are we from scaling up next-pixel prediction?
ID: 2511.08704
Authors: Xinchen Yan, Chen Liang, Lijun Yu et al.
Date: 2025-11-11
Categories: cs.CV, cs.LG
Abstract: This paper investigates the scaling properties of autoregressive next-pixel prediction, a simple, end-to-end yet under-explored framework for unified vision models. Starting with images at resolutions...

=== 128 ===
Title: 4D-RGPT: Toward Region-level 4D Understanding via Perceptual Distillation
ID: 2512.17012
Authors: Chiao-An Yang, Ryo Hachiuma, Sifei Liu et al.
Date: 2025-12-18
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Despite advances in Multimodal LLMs (MLLMs), their ability to reason over 3D structures and temporal dynamics remains limited, constrained by weak 4D perception and temporal understanding. Existing 3D...

=== 129 ===
Title: G$^2$VLM: Geometry Grounded Vision Language Model with Unified 3D Reconstruction and Spatial Reasoning
ID: 2511.21688
Authors: Wenbo Hu, Jingli Lin, Yilin Long et al.
Date: 2025-11-26
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.CL
Abstract: Vision-Language Models (VLMs) still lack robustness in spatial intelligence, demonstrating poor performance on spatial understanding and reasoning tasks. We attribute this gap to the absence of a visu...

=== 130 ===
Title: Multimodal Spatial Reasoning in the Large Model Era: A Survey and Benchmarks
ID: 2510.25760
Authors: Xu Zheng, Zihao Dongfang, Lutao Jiang et al.
Date: 2025-10-29
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Humans possess spatial reasoning abilities that enable them to understand spaces through multimodal observations, such as vision and sound. Large multimodal reasoning models extend these abilities by ...

=== 131 ===
Title: Revisiting Multimodal Positional Encoding in Vision-Language Models
ID: 2510.23095
Authors: Jie Huang, Xuejing Liu, Sibo Song et al.
Date: 2025-10-27
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Multimodal position encoding is essential for vision-language models, yet there has been little systematic investigation into multimodal position encoding. We conduct a comprehensive analysis of multi...

=== 132 ===
Title: Unifying Perception and Action: A Hybrid-Modality Pipeline with Implicit Visual Chain-of-Thought for Robotic Action Generation
ID: 2511.19859
Authors: Xiangkai Ma, Lekai Xing, Han Zhang et al.
Date: 2025-11-25
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Vision-Language-Action (VLA) models built upon Chain-of-Thought (CoT) have achieved remarkable success in advancing general-purpose robotic agents, owing to its significant perceptual comprehension. R...

=== 133 ===
Title: Scaling Spatial Intelligence with Multimodal Foundation Models
ID: 2511.13719
Authors: Zhongang Cai, Ruisi Wang, Chenyang Gu et al.
Date: 2025-11-17
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI, cs.LG, cs.MM, cs.RO
Abstract: Despite remarkable progress, multimodal foundation models still exhibit surprising deficiencies in spatial intelligence. In this work, we explore scaling up multimodal foundation models to cultivate s...

=== 134 ===
Title: LatBot: Distilling Universal Latent Actions for Vision-Language-Action Models
ID: 2511.23034
Authors: Zuolei Li, Xingyu Gao, Xiaofan Wang et al.
Date: 2025-11-28
Categories: cs.RO
Abstract: Learning transferable latent actions from large-scale object manipulation videos can significantly enhance generalization in downstream robotics tasks, as such representations are agnostic to differen...

=== 135 ===
Title: Motion4D: Learning 3D-Consistent Motion and Semantics for 4D Scene Understanding
ID: 2512.03601
Authors: Haoran Zhou, Gim Hee Lee
Date: 2025-12-03
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Recent advancements in foundation models for 2D vision have substantially improved the analysis of dynamic scenes from monocular videos. However, despite their strong generalization capabilities, thes...

=== 136 ===
Title: SpatialTree: How Spatial Abilities Branch Out in MLLMs
ID: 2512.20617
Authors: Yuxi Xiao, Longfei Li, Shen Yan et al.
Date: 2025-12-23
Categories: cs.CV
Abstract: Cognitive science suggests that spatial ability develops progressively-from perception to reasoning and interaction. Yet in multimodal LLMs (MLLMs), this hierarchy remains poorly understood, as most s...

=== 137 ===
Title: WaymoQA: A Multi-View Visual Question Answering Dataset for Safety-Critical Reasoning in Autonomous Driving
ID: 2511.20022
Authors: Seungjun Yu, Seonho Lee, Namho Kim et al.
Date: 2025-11-25
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: Recent advancements in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have shown strong understanding of driving scenes, drawing interest in their application to autonomous driving. However, high-level reas...

=== 138 ===
Title: Map-World: Masked Action planning and Path-Integral World Model for Autonomous Driving
ID: 2511.20156
Authors: Bin Hu, Zijian Lu, Haicheng Liao et al.
Date: 2025-11-25
Categories: cs.CV, cs.RO
Abstract: Motion planning for autonomous driving must handle multiple plausible futures while remaining computationally efficient. Recent end-to-end systems and world-model-based planners predict rich multi-mod...

=== 139 ===
Title: Training Large Language Models to Reason in a Continuous Latent Space
ID: 2412.06769
Authors: Shibo Hao, Sainbayar Sukhbaatar, DiJia Su et al.
Date: 2024-12-09
Categories: cs.CL
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are typically constrained to reason in the language space, where they express the reasoning process through a chain-of-thought (CoT) to solve complex problems. However, th...

=== 140 ===
Title: SAM 3: Segment Anything with Concepts
ID: 2511.16719
Authors: Nicolas Carion, Laura Gustafson, Yuan-Ting Hu et al.
Date: 2025-11-20
Categories: cs.CV, cs.AI
Abstract: We present Segment Anything Model (SAM) 3, a unified model that detects, segments, and tracks objects in images and videos based on concept prompts, which we define as either short noun phrases (e.g.,...

